[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; All right.
&gt;&gt; 好的
Good evening, everyone.
大家晚上好
My name is Eugene.
我的名字是 Eugene
I'm an engineer on the Messages
我是 Messages 团队的工程师
team and I am super excited to
今晚我很高兴能来这里
be here tonight to speak with
与大家聊聊
you about what's new in iMessage
iMessage 各类应用的
apps.
新功能
Let's dive in here.
我们就直奔主题吧
We've got a couple of things on
今晚我们计划向大家介绍
the agenda this evening.
几项内容
First one, we want to show off a
首先 我们想向大家稍微炫耀一下
little bit of what's new in the
iOS 11 中 iMessage App 领域的
iMessage app area in iOS 11.
新功能
Some of the stuff you saw in the
除了大家在 Keynote 里看到的以外
keynote plus a little bit more.
还有一些其他内容
After that, we're going to be
然后我们会向大家展示
introducing our awesome new
我们非常出色的
Direct Send API.
全新 Direct Send API
After that, my colleagues Jay
在此之后 我的同事 Jay 和 Stephen
and Stephen will be coming on
会上台来
stage to talk to you about our
跟大家聊聊
new Live Message Layouts.
我们全新的 Live Message Layouts
And finally, we'll be wrapping
最后 我们会跟大家分享
up the talk with a couple best
几个关于 iMessage 各类应用的
practices tips and tricks for
最佳操作技巧
your iMessage apps.
并结束今天的会议
So a lot of what we're talking
今年我们要讨论的很多功能
about this year builds off the
都是依据我们去年
fundamentals that we established
使用 iOS 10
last year with iOS 10 and the
并推出 Message 框架
introduction of the Messages
而建立的基础原则
framework.
之上
So if you need a refresher about
如果大家需要总体回顾一下
the Messages framework or
Message 框架
iMessage apps in general, we
或是 iMessage 的各类应用
highly recommend watching our
我们强烈建议大家去看看
previous year session iMessage
我们去年的会议
Apps and Stickers Part 2, which
“iMessage Apps and Stickers”第二场
is available on the developer
通过开发者门户网站
portal.
就可以观看
So give that a look if you'd
如果大家需要的话
like a refresher.
可以回顾一下
So let's get into the cool
现在我们就来深入了解一下
stuff.
这些炫酷的功能
What's new in the Messages app
Message 应用领域里有哪些
area.
新功能
So as you all saw on Monday,
就像大家在周一看到的那样
we've updated a little bit of
我们对 iOS 11 里 Message 应用的用户界面
the Messages app UI for iOS 11.
进行了一些升级
So I just saw on Monday when a
我在周一刚看到
user enters the conversation now
当用户在键入对话时
we put all the app icons right
所有 App 图标
there at the bottom of the
都被放在了屏幕底部
screen which makes it really
这就使得用户在
easy for users to launch
键入对话时
applications right when entering
能够更方便地启动
a conversation.
启动应用程序
As with iOS 10, your application
与 iOS 10 的情况一样
still lives in kind of the
你的应用程序基本上
keyboard area but we still have
存在于键盘区域
the application icons down at
但是我们在屏幕下方也放置了
the bottom.
应用图标
Now users can scroll this
现在用户可以
application list left and right
左右滚动应用列表
to quickly find the application
快速找到他们
they want to launch.
想要启动的应用
We've also divided the strip
我们还把这条区域
into two different sections, as
分割成了两块
you can see up here.
大家可以从大屏幕上看到
The left-hand side we have the
左边区域是
users favorite section which is
用户偏好的应用区域
ordered by the user, and on the
它是由用户进行排序的
right-hand side we have the most
右边区域是
recently used applications.
最近使用过的应用程序
So users can also rearrange
这样用户可以重新整理一番
their applications out of the
从最近使用区域里拿出来一部分应用
recent section and into their
放进偏好应用区域
favorites for easy use and for
这样使用起来更方便
accessibility right when they
在键入对话时
enter the conversation.
也更容易接入
So we think this is a great way
我们认为对于用户来说
for users to enter a
这是一种很棒的键入对话方式
conversation, tap the app they
只要轻点一下
want and be able to use your
自己想要使用的 App
application immediately.
就可以马上使用它
One really cool change their
今年还有
making this year revolves around
一个很酷的改变
how we handle app installations.
是有关我们对 App 安装的处理方法
So now in iOS 11 if you download
现在 在 iOS 11 里
an application from the iMessage
如果你从 iMessage App Store
app store or you download from
或是从我们原来的 App Store 里
our primary app store we will
下载一个应用
enable your application by
我们在默认状态下启用你的 App
default and the Messages app
以及 Message
drawer.
应用抽屉
In addition --
除此之外
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
So in addition, we will order
除此之外  我们还会
your applications icon to the
把你的应用图标
very first item in the most
归整排列到最近使用的应用
recently used apps so users can
的最前面 这样用户就可以
find it easily and launch the
更快找到  并且即刻启动
application immediately.
这个应用
So there's just a couple changes
以上就是我们对
that we have for the Messages
Messages App 用户界面做出的
app UI.
几个改变
A lot of it you guys have today.
在座很多人已经用到了
Next up we have our brand new
下面将为大家奉上我们全新的
Direct Send API.
Direct Send API
We're super excited to share
我们非常兴奋
this with all of you.
想和大家一起分享
So in iOS 10, the only way to
在 iOS 10 里  从 Message 应用
share content out of your
向外分享内容的唯一办法
Messages app would be to call an
就是调用一个 Insert API
insert API which puts your
这个 API 将把你的信息
message into the Messages entry
放入 Message 输入视图
view.
里面
And so while this works great
虽然这个方法
for many applications, for some
对于很多应用程序都很好用
user experiences like this game
但对于有些用户体验来说 比如这个游戏
when the users say makes the
用户所说的话将使得
game move next logical step
这个游戏朝着下一个逻辑步骤发展
would probably be the message
情况很可能就是
actually being sent and
信息确实被发送
inserting that message into the
而且被添加到输入视图
entry view kind of adds an extra
有些像是额外地
tap.
点击了一次
So we thought this year how can
所以 今年我们想着
we make this easier, how can we
怎么能让它简单一点
make this a better user
如何能够让用户体验
experience?
提升一下
So in iOS 11 you can send any
在以前的正常情况下
content that you would have
你会把消息从自己的应用程序里
normally inserted into the
直接插入 Messages 的输入视图
Messages entry view directly
在 iOS 11 里 你可以直接发送
from your application.
任何这一类的消息
So how does this work?
这是如何实现的呢？
In iOS 10 we introduced MS
在 iOS 10 中 我们引进了
conversation which defined the
MS Conversation 它定义了
following insert APIs.
定义了以下的 Insert API
Insert message ,insert sticker,
insertMessage insertSticker
insertText, and insertAttachment
insertText 还有 insertAttachment
which supports any of our
insertAttachment 它们能支持我们任何
standard Messages attachment
标准化的 Messages 附件
types.
类型
In iOS 11 we have a very simple
iOS 11 里有一个很简单的
analogist API called Send
类比推理 API
Message, Send Sticker, Send
名为 Send Message Send Sticker
Text, and Send Attachment.
Send Text 和 Send Attachment
So calling into anyone of these
调用其中任何一个 API
will bypass the Messages entry
都会绕过 Message 输入视图
view and insert -- send you a
并立即在会话中
message immediately in the
向你发送一条
conversation.
信息
So really quick and easy API.
非常快捷好用的 API
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
So you may ask which API --
你们可能会问哪个 API
which user experience is best
哪个项用户体验
for my application, both Insert
最适合我的应用
Draft and Send Message APIs are
Insert Draft 和 Send Message API
first party citizens in iOS 11,
都是 iOS 11 中的一等公民
and it's up to you to decide
至于哪一个最适合
which one is best for your
你的应用
application.
这要由你来决定
So the Insert Draft API is still
所以说  Insert Draft API 仍是
the recommended API for most
在多数应用中推荐使用的 API
applications as it allows for
因为它能带来更丰富的
richer composition experience.
编写体验
For example, user can insert a
例如 用户可以插入一条信息
message and then say append a
然后 比如说 在信息末尾
comment to the end of the
增加一句评价
message, or send with a screen
或是附送一个屏幕特效
effect or a full screen moment.
或全屏动态
So it's a really great way to
它真是一个很好的方法
enrich the content that you
能让你原本要发送的信息
would already be sending.
内容更显丰富
In addition, it gives the user
除此之外
an opportunity to verify the
它让用户还有机会
content that will be sent which
更正要发送的内容
is extremely important.
这一点非常重要
On the other hand, Direct Send
另一方面 Direct Send API
API offers a superfast quick and
为大家提供了超级迅速和便捷的
easy user experience that's
用户体验
great for, say, games and stuff
这非常适合类似于游戏或
like we saw above.
我们前面看到的那些东西
So it's great for any
在任何应用里
application where the insert
插入流程里包含点击输入视图按钮
flow has tapping the entry view
这很不简单
button feel like an extra step
你可能感觉这是额外增加的步骤
that you really don't need.
是你完全不需要的
However, when using this API it
但是 在使用这个 API 时
is extremely important to
尤其重要的一点是
maintain user trust in your
保持用户对你的
application.
这个应用的信任
So it's important to very
所以 重要的是十分明确地提示用户
clearly indicate to the user
究竟是要发送什么内容
exactly what content is going to
同时还应当
be sent and also to clearly
清楚地向用户表明
denote to the user exactly what
你这个 App 里究竟有
user interaction or interface
什么样的用户交互或界面元素
element within your application
会在你的应用里
will trigger send.
触发发送
So to help promote a great user
所以 通过 Direct Send API Message
experience with a direct send
来帮助用户大幅提升体验
API Messages enforces a couple
就给这类 API 的使用
requirements on this APIs use.
施加了几项要求
Firstly, your application must
首先 你的应用必须是
be the visible Messages app on
屏幕上可见的
screen.
Message 应用
As you may know, your Messages
大家可能知道
app extension may be running in
你们的 Message 应用扩展可能是
the background within Messages
在 Message 的后台运行
and not actually be the current
而确实不在当前的
foreground application.
前台应用
So first requirement is your
所以第一项要求就是
application must be visible.
你的应用必须可见
In addition, our target user
除此之外 对于这个功能
experience for this is to have
我们的目标用户体验是
the user tap the screen or
是要让用户轻点屏幕
interact with your application
或与你的应用交互
and then to have a send be
然后触发发送
So to facilitate this, Messages
为了让这种操作更为便利  Message
will detect user interaction on
还将探测用户
your app and allow for a direct
在你 App 上的交互
send API call to be made upon
并在探测用户交互时
detection of that user
允许调用一个直接发送的
interaction.
API
Subsequent direct send calls
后续的直接发送调用将失败
will fail until we detect
直到我们探测到
another user interaction, so
另一种用户交互
kind of keeping with one-to-one
某种程度上保持着一一对应
the user press something on your
用户按下屏幕上某处
screen and a send is allowed.
就会获准发送内容
So to help you as developers
为了帮助在座的各位开发人员
understand what's happening with
能够理解 发送 API 到底是
the send API, we are introducing
怎样的情形
two new air codes, MSMessage air
我们要介绍两个新的 Air 代码
codes.
MSMessage Air 代码
We have
我们现在有这两个代码
sendwithoutRecentInteraction and
一个是 sendwithoutRecentInteraction
sendwhileNotVisible.
另一个是 sendwhileNotVisible
So as always, use great air
与往常一样 使用出色的 Air 处理方法
handling so your application can
这样可以使你的应用
catch these dates.
才能找准日期
And that's Direct Send.
这就是 Direct Send
It's very simple.
非常简单
I think it's going to be a great
我觉得它对于
user experience for the apps
它自身适用的那些 App 来说
where it makes sense for.
这将是很棒的用户体验
Definitely consider whether
大家一定要考虑一下
Insert Draft or Send makes the
究竟是 Insert Draft 还是 Send
most sense for your application,
最适合你的应用
and we're very excited to see
我们很高兴地期盼着大家使用它
what you-guys can build with it.
而构建的成果
All right.
好了
So next I'd like to invite
接下来我想邀请
Stephen up stage to introduce
Stephen 上台
you to Live Message Layouts.
介绍一下 Live Message Layouts
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Hi everyone.
&gt;&gt; 嗨 大家好
So today I'm excited to return
今天 我很开心能回到台上
to the stage to you to talk to
跟大家聊聊
you about Live Message Layouts.
Live Message Layouts
Now in iOS 10 we introduced
在 iOS 10 中
Messages framework and the
我们引入了 Message 框架
ability for you to bring your
能让大家
app experience right into
把 App 体验直接带入
Messages.
Message 当中
When you would build your
当你想要构建你的
iMessage app, your app could be
iMessage 应用时
shown here in the keyboard area
你的 App 会在 Message 的
in Messages or in a full screen
键盘区域显示 或以全屏展示
presentation, and these would be
状态显示  这些可能是
the compact and expanded
你能够使用的
presentation styles that you
简洁和扩展型的
could use.
展示风格
And then when you would send the
接着 当你要发送信息时
message your app would use a
你的 App 会使用
template driven -- or we would
一个模板驱动  或者说  我们会使用
use a template driven layout
一个模板驱动布局方法
approach for your app message.
来用于你的 App 信息
Now this template layout had
现在这个模板布局有
customization objects or options
自定义对象或选项
such as image and the text
比如图像
properties here, and it allowed
和这里的文本属性
you to provide some pretty good
它允许你提供一些优质
rich app messages, however, it's
而丰富的 App 信息
still limited by what the
不过它仍然还是受制于
template provides.
模板提供的内容
In iOS 11, I'm excited to
现在我很高兴地向大家宣布
announce that you can now
在 iOS 11 中
completely customize what your
大家可以用这些 liveLayout
app messages look like using
来彻底地自定义
these liveLayouts.
你的 App 信息了
So this is actually a view
这个视图其实就是
provided by the application
App 应用自身
itself here in the Messages
在 Message 文本里
transcript.
提供的
The app could also drive a view
这个 App 也可以驱动一个视图
as a draft message, and in fact
作为草稿信息
can provide custom views to
它实际上可以提供自定义视图
represent many messages
从而将多条信息
simultaneously in the
同时呈现在
transcript.
文本里
Of course we support the world
当然 在我们支持的所有情况下
where maybe your app isn't the
你的 App 可能并不是
only one on screen, but really
屏幕上唯一的 App  但我们真的
we only care about your app.
只在意你的 App
We're here to talk to you about
今天我们来这里就是要
that today.
跟大家探讨这一点
So I'd like to give you a quick
我想给大家快速演示一下
demo of what that looks like in
它在运行中是什么样的
action.
状态
So here I have a simple iMessage
现在我手里有一个简单的 iMessage 应用
app that I've built called Event
是我构建的  它名叫 Event Countdown
Countdown, and this is just a
这只是一个简单的列表
simple list of upcoming events
罗列了近期要参加的活动
that I'm excited about and want
都是我迫切想要参加
to share with my friends via
还想通过我的 Message
Messages.
与朋友分享的内容
So for example, if I tap the
例如 如果我轻点这里的批处理
batch here you'll see a
你们会看到一个
completely custom message is
完全自定义的信息
presented here as a draft
以草稿信息的形式呈现在
message.
这里
It's live updating, it has this
它是实时更新  它拥有
great countdown that's building
出色的倒计时功能
anticipation for the upcoming
让你对近期将要到来的活动
event.
充满期待
And when I send it, that same
我发送它的时候
view is put in the transcript
同样的视图会被置入
that would be seen on the other
传输另一端可以看到的
side.
文本里
In fact, if we go into the
事实上 如果我们进入接收方
recipient side or to see what a
或许可以看看
recipient might have sent or the
接收方可能发送了什么
other side might have sent, here
或另一边可能发送了什么
I have an invitation from
现在我有一份邀请
Eugene.
它来自 Eugene
This is a similar app message,
这是一个相似的 App 信息
but my iMessage app has chosen
但我的 iMessage 应用已经选择
to render a completely different
将一个完全不同的视图
view on the receiver side.
呈现在接收方一侧
I'm representing an unaccepted
好 我马上要展示一个
invitation at this point.
未被接受的邀请
If I tap this app message bubble
如果我轻点这里的 App 气泡
here, I mark the event as
我就把这个事件标记为“已接受”
accepted and now it switches to
现在它切换到了
that live countdown mode.
实时倒计时模式
I was able to do all that
在这种情况下
without even having to launch my
我甚至不用启动 iMessage 应用
iMessage app in this context.
就能完成所有这些操作
Now here in the top right I have
现在右上方有一个
a little infoButton.
小的 infoButton
Not all experiences are
并不是所有的体验
appropriate to try to shove into
都适合用来塞进 App 信息
an app message.
里面的
By tapping this infoButton, I
轻点这个 infoButton
can actually request that my app
我就可以真正发出请求
be presented in a different
让我的 App 以一种
presentation style to see more
不同的展示风格来显示
information about my event.
这样可以看到我更多的活动信息
So I hope you can see that here
我希望大家能在这里看到
with Live Message Layouts you
通过 Live Message Layouts
can build a really rich user
你就可以构建
experience, complete with
真正精彩的用户体验
interactions and live updating
交互和内容实时更新让它完满
content, and it's really easy to
而且操作起来确实
do.
很简单
So let's talk about how this
那么我们来谈谈它的
works.
工作原理
So here when the iMessage app is
当 iMessage 应用
being shown in the compact
以简洁的展示风格而呈现时
presentation style, we have
我们用一则实例进行了
instantiated an instance of the
具体说明  这个例子是
MSMessages app view controller
MSMessage App 视图控制器的子类
subclass and configured it in
我们把它配置为
the compact presentation style.
简洁型展示风格
When an app message with a
当带有一个 liveLayout 的 App 消息
liveLayout is shown on screen,
出现在屏幕时
we'll instantiate another
我们会提供同一基本类的
instance of that same base class
另一个具体实例
and configure it with a
并将其配置为
transcript presentation style.
文本展示风格
In fact, for each message
实际上 对于文本里
displayed in the transcript we
展示的每一条信息
will instantiate a new instance
我们都会从同一分类中
of this class configured again
举出新的实例
in that transcript presentation
然后再把它配置为
style.
文本展示风格
There is a strict one-to-one
这些实例
relationship between these
以及它们展现在屏幕上的
instances and an app message
某条 App 信息之间
that they represent on screen.
存在着严格的逐一对应关系
So that's a quick overview of
以上就是关于 Live Message Layouts
Live Message Layouts.
一个快速的概述
Now to walk you through more of
接下来我要带领大家了解更多
the API and how to get started,
关于 API 以及如何启用它的内容
I'd like to invite Jay on stage.
现在我想邀请 Jay 上台
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Well thanks, Stephen, for the
谢谢 Stephen 的介绍
introduction.
非常感谢
My name is Jay and I'm here to
我是 Jay
introduce to you some of the new
我想为大家介绍
APIs we've added for Live
我们给 Live Message Layout
Message Layout.
添加的这些新 API
So let's get started.
那么我们就开始吧
As some of you may be familiar,
在座各位可能有人很清楚
you were able to customize your
你们可以用
app bubble using
MSMessageLayout
MSMessageLayout.
自定义你的 App 气泡
With existing MSMessage template
如果使用当前的 MSMessage
layout you're only able to
模板布局  你只能对有限的
customize a limited set of
几组外观进行自定义
appearances such as captions and
例如标题
images.
还有图像
In iOS 11, to support a fully
在 iOS 11 中
customizable bubble we're adding
为了支持气泡的完全自定义功能
a new subclass
我们添加了新的子类
MSMessageLiveLayout.
MSMessageLiveLayout
So let's take look at this real
让我们来快速地
quick.
看一下
As you can see, there aren't
大家可以看到  这里
that many things to fill out as
要填写的东西并不多
you have to do for the template
不像模板布局要求的
layout.
那么多
Well that's because now you have
这是因为现在
the opportunity to fully express
你可以充分表明
how these app bubbles should
你希望呈现怎样的 App 气泡
look like.
外观
Though you may have noticed that
尽管大家可能注意到了
there is one property called
这里有一个属性 它的名称是
Alternate Layout and so what is
Alternate Layout
this?
可这又是什么呢
Now there will be a few
现在会有一些实例
instances where your app bubble
在这些例子里  你的 App 气泡
won't be supported by the
在接收设备上
receiving devices.
不受支持
In cases such as they don't have
原因可能是  接收设备并没有安装
your extension installed or
你的 Extension
they're just running on older
或它们只是运行在
Apple iOS versions, iOS, macOS,
旧的 Apple iOS 版本 iOS macOS
or watchOS.
或 watchOS 上
So in these scenarios, they'll
在这些场景里
be seeing this template layout
它们会将这个模板布局看作是
as a fallback representation by
一个备选表达法
if they can actually support
如果它们能真正
their extension then they'll be
支持它们的 Extension
seeing the bubble on the right.
就会在右侧看见气泡
So how do we use this API?
那么我们如何使用这个 API 呢？
It's very similar to how you did
其实这跟你在 iOS 10 中的操作
in iOS 10.
很相似
First, create the template
首先 要创建模板
layout.
布局
And with a template layout
然后用模板布局
you're going to create
去创建
liveLayout.
liveLayout
And with a liveLayout say it's a
有了 liveLayout
message and send.
比如说  有一条信息 然后发送
So really similar to what we did
这跟我们在 iOS 10 里的操作
in iOS 10.
很相似
So that was it for the
这就是关于
MSMessageLiveLayout.
MSMessageLiveLayout 的内容
We have some new additions in
我们把一些新的功能增添到了
MSMessagesAppViewController.
MSMessagesAppViewController
Now as some of you may be
大家有人可能很清楚
familiar, this was the principle
这是扩展点中的
class through extension point.
主要类
So by configuring this view
通过配置这个
controller you're able to
视图控制器
customize the appearance in your
你就能够自定义
app in the keyboard area, in the
App 键盘区域
compact mode.
在简洁模式下的外观
So the bubbles in the transcript
文本里的气泡
are also backed by View
也受视图控制器的支持
Controller, and in fact they
其实它们
have the same class.
有同样的类
Okay. So what does this mean?
好了 那么这意味着什么呢
That means that this view right
这意味着
here in the bottom and that view
在底部的这个视图
on the top are coming from the
和在顶部的那个视图
same class.
来自于同一个类
So to distinguish these two
为了区分这二者
cases we've added a new
我们添加了新的
presentation style transcript.
展示风格文本
So when it comes time to
一旦需要对这些
configuring these view
视图控制器进行配置时
controllers, you can use a
你可以将
combination of presentationStyle
presentationStyle
and selectedMessage to determine
和 selectedMessage 结合起来使用
what you want to show in your
从而决定你想展示在
view controller.
视图控制器中的内容
And one really simple pattern
你可以遵循一个
you can follow is something
很简单的模式
along the line of path factory
那就是在某种程度上遵循 Python 的工厂模式
pattern where you can return
你可以根据这些属性的状态而决定
appropriate child view
在这一模式中
controller depending on the
返回适当的
state of these properties.
子视图控制器
So you're going to have one for
所以  你会将一个控制器用于文本风格
transcript and one for compact.
另一个用于简洁模式
So if you're already following a
如果你已经遵循了
similar pattern and code it will
一个相似的模式并进行编码
look something like this.
看起来就会像这样
So for the compact case we have
对于简洁的风格
a helper method
我们有一个辅助方法
presentSummaryViewController and
那就是 presentSummaryViewController
this helper method you will
有了这个辅助方法
create the right child view
你就可以创建正确的
controller and configure a view
子视图控制器
controller appropriately.
并恰当地配置视图控制器
For the case of expanded, you'll
至于扩展风格
have another helper method
你会获得另一个辅助方法
presentDetailViewController and
即 presentDetailViewController
will do something very similar
它的功能与你
to what you did for the compact
在简洁风格中的操作
case.
十分相似
So to handle another case for
为了处理文本风格的另一种情况
the transcript, we can just have
我们还有另外的一种
another helper method something
辅助方法
along the line of
它是按照
presentTranscriptViewController.
presentTranscriptViewController 来进行的
So that was it for the
以上就是关于
presentation style, but we
展示风格的介绍
actually have one more thing to
其实我们还要分享另一项内容
go over before you get this live
然后再跟大家聊一聊
bubble started.
实时气泡
And that is sizing.
我们现在要谈的  就是调整尺寸
Now, the view controllers are
现在 视图控制器
intended to use for transcript
本意是要用于文本
will conform to the new protocol
它将遵照一项新的协议
called MSMessagesAppTranscript
协议名为
Presentation.
MSMessagesAppTranscriptPresentation
It has one method called
它有一个方法
ContentSizeThatFits.
叫做 ContentSizeThatFits
In this function, return a size
在这个功能里
that best represents your view
会返回一个最能代表
in the transcript.
你文本内视图的尺寸
So to illustrate, here's an
为了解释清楚  我们来
example.
举个例子
Now, we want our size to always
现在 我们想让尺寸
fit all the sub views nicely
能一直完美地契合所有的 subView
without getting clipped or any
不会被剪切  或是有
extras base or anything like
多余的底边  以及其他类似
that.
情况
For this particular example, we
关于这个具体样例
have the map view timer and the
我们设有地图视图、计时器
button.
还有按钮
And we decided that we'd only
我们决定只关注
care about the size of the map
地图视图的大小
view or the timer changing, but
或计时器的变化
we want the button to adjust
但我们想让按钮
accordingly based on the system
根据系统字体做出
font.
相应调整
So let's give it a static
我们来给
number, 217, for the map view
地图视图和计时器
and the timer, and then the line
一个静态数字 217
hide right here will be the size
这里的行高就会成为
of the button that takes the
按钮的尺寸
system font into consideration.
并将系统字体考虑在内
So by adding these two numbers
把这两个数字输入
we'll get the right size or the
我们会得到正确的尺寸
right height that encompasses
或正确的行高  其中包含了
all the sub views in our view.
我们视图中所有的 subView
So with this configuration, I
根据这个配置
think the height is about 235
我觉得高度应是
points.
235 点
Now keep in mind that this
请大家记住
function will be called again
如果文本尺寸
when there is a change in
场所和系统字体
transcript size, change in
出现了变化
locale or change in system font.
这个功能将会再次被调用
In these events, these functions
在上述情况下  这些功能
will be called again for a new
将被再次调用  从而生成新的
size.
尺寸
So here's an example of change
这里举一个系统字体
in system font.
发生改变的例子
As you can see, the fonts are
大家可以看到
slightly bigger.
现在字体变大了一点
In this case, we just said that
这种情况 我们刚刚说过了
we didn't care about the map
我们关心的并不是地图视图
view or the timer growing or
或计时器的时长变化
shrinking so let's look at the
那么我们就看一下
same 217.
同样的 217
But because we're using a
然而  因为我们给按钮
dynamic font for the button, it
使用的是动态字体
automatically picked up a size.
它便自动选择了一个尺寸
And with this configuration, you
有了这个配置  你就可以
can appropriately return 244.
妥当地返回 244
We'll take this value and resize
我们会接受这个值
your view accordingly.
并相应地调整你的视图尺寸
So that was a lot of talking.
说了这么多
To summarize everything I just
我想用一个
talked about I'd like to show a
快速的编码演示
quick code demo.
来总结我刚才说的这些
And I know a lot of you-guys are
我知道你们当中有许多人
very eager to be at the bash so
非常期待参加聚会
we'll work on a sample app that
所以我们会创建一个样品 App
shows you a countdown timer to
用来显示聚会的倒数
the bash.
计时器
Okay. Cool.
好了 真不错
So we have our nice X Code here
这是我们很棒的 Xcode
and this is the device I have on
这是我现在放在
the table right now.
桌子上的设备
So in this demo I'd like to show
在这个演示中 我要展示
how you can extend an existing
如何扩展现有的 iMessage 应用
iMessage app and start using our
并开始使用我们的
LiveMessageLayout.
LiveMessageLayout
So if you remain on iMessage app
如果你停留在 iMessage 应用
it will look something like
它的界面就会呈现出
this.
这个样子
So you have an app in the
那么  当你有一个 App
compact mode and when you're
处于简洁模式
trying to send it will show a
你尝试发送时
template layout.
它会显示一个模板布局
So how about we start using
我们不如开始采用
LiveLayout instead
LiveLayout
templateLayout as showing on the
而不是展架上的
shelf?
templateLayout
So let's get to the code.
让我们进入代码部分
And here I'm in
我现在
MSMessagesAppViewController sub
在 MSMessagesAppViewController 的
class.
子类
And somewhere in this code were
在这个代码的某处
probably creating a template
可能将要创建一个
layout.
模板布局
So let's look for that.
我们来找找看
Found it. So we have this helper
找到了 我们有这个辅助功能
function called sendMessage and
叫作 sendMessage
it seems like we are creating
看来我们要创建
the message, configuring it,
信息 对它进行配置
create a templateLayout and then
创建一个 templateLayout
set that layout to the message
然后再将布局放入信息
and we're inserting it into the
现在我们将它插入
conversation.
对话
So I think this is a great place
我觉得这个地方很适合
to start using our liveLayout
启用我们的 liveLayout
objects.
对象
So here I'm going to go ahead
接下来我要继续
and create a liveLayout.
创建一个 liveLayout
There's the template layout.
这里是模板布局
And then we can set that as
接下来我们可以把它设置为
Messages layout property.
Message 布局属性
And let's see -- okay.
看一下 好了
So with this change you should
在改动之后
be seeing a liveLayout.
大家应该能看到一个 liveLayout
And this is definitely a
这肯定是一个 liveLayout
liveLayout, but this doesn't
但看起来有些
look right.
不太对劲
This actually looks exactly like
这个看起来其实很像
what you just saw in the compact
刚才在简洁模式中看到的
mode.
那样
So what went wrong?
哪里出问题了呢
Let's get back to the code and
我们返回到代码
let's try to find out where
试着找一找
we're actually creating this
大家在简洁模式中见到过
table view controller that you
我们实际创建
see in the compact mode.
这个表视图控制器的地方
And a good place to check that
现在有一个地方
right now, I'm going to go into
需要马上查看一下
willBecomeActive, okay, I see
我要进入 willBecomeActive  好
updatePresentation.
我看到了 updatePresentation
See what this does.
看看它在做什么
Oh and I see
噢我看到了
presentViewController.
presentViewController
Now this seems like a problem
这个看起来像是问题所在
right here.
就是这里
For anything that is not
对于所有未展开的内容
expanded we're always creating a
我们都会创建一个
table view controller and, as
表格视图控制器
mentioned before, the same view
正如先前提到的
controller class is used for
同一个视图控制器分类
both transcript, compact and
可以用来支持文本型 简洁型和
expanded so we need to handle
扩展型风格 在这个案例中
case for transcript which is not
我们需要处理的是文本风格
supporting this code right now.
而现在 文本却并不支持这个代码
I'm going to leave this code as
我要让这个代码
it is now.
保持原样
I'm going to create a new
我要创建一个新函数
function so they can start
这样 它们可以开始
handling this case.
处理这个文本的案例
So I have this
所以我现在有了这个
presentTranscriptView and I have
presentTranscriptView
this [inaudible], I have to know
也有了代码 我必须要知道
if it's for me or if it's
它是否要发给我 或是否有待发送
pending because I want to decide
因为我要决定
if I need to show the invitation
我是否需要显示
button or not.
邀请按钮
So now that I have this
那么  我现在既然有了这个
transcriptView I can go ahead
transcriptView
and add it to a sub view with
就可以继续用 Auto Layout Magic
the Auto Layout Magic.
把它添加到一个 subView 里
Then I have to call this method
然后  我要在某个地方调用这个方法
somewhere so I'm going to go
所以 我打算回到
back to updatePresentation.
updatePresentation
It's right here.
它就在这里
And here I can start configuring
我可以在这里开始
this viewController for
给文本配置
transcript.
这个 viewController
TranscriptView, event,
TranscriptView 事件 对话
conversation, and for everything
还有其他所有内容
else I'm just going to do what
我现在准备做
we've always been doing for
我们为了支持简洁和扩展模式
compact and expanded.
而一直在做的事情
Cool. So let's see how this
很好 我们来看看
change will look like.
经过这次改动  会变成什么样
So with this change you should
在这次改动过后
always see the event detail in
你应该一直能看到事件详情
app bubble.
出现在 App 的气泡框里
So it's succeeded.
所以事情办成了
So I'm going back to our device.
我现在回到我们的设备
Right. Shut up.
好的 停
Cool. So I see something now,
很好 我现在看到了一些东西
but it is kind of big and I
但它有点儿大
don't know where the map view
我不知道地图视图去了哪里
went but we're getting there.
但我们已经达成目的
As you can see there's like an
你可以看到 这里有一块
awkward wide blue space.
看起来很别扭的蓝色区域
It is definitely bigger than I
它比我预想的要
expected.
大很多
So what went wrong is seems like
所以哪里又出问题了
we didn't implement content size
可能是我们没有执行
that fits the last part of this
符合这个 liveLayout 接受条件里
liveLayout adoption.
最后一部分的内容尺寸
So I'm going to go ahead and
所以我要赶快
implement that real quick.
执行这个内容尺寸
And then from the demo, from the
根据本次演示 根据幻灯片内容
slides, you wanted to height to
你原本想要把高度设置为 217
be about 217, and then for the
至于标题按钮
title button you want it to by
你想将其设置为动态的
dynamic and it was fetched from
它先从 transcriptView.titleFont
transcriptView.titleFont and
然后从 lineHeight
then lineHeight.
获取而来
We want our width to be the
我们想把宽度尽可能地设置为
maximum width possible which is
最大宽度
the path and size parameter so
即路径和尺寸的参数上限
we can just return the exact
所以我们可以直接返回
value.
确切的值
And then for the height, we can
然后是高度
add these two values.
我们可以添加这两个值
And this would be a good size to
这个尺寸刚好可以
return two messages.
返回两条信息
So let's see how that looks
那么我们来看看现在
like.
成什么样了
Okay.
好了
So it's loaded.
它加载好了
Much better.
好多了
This is what we saw in the demo.
这就是我们在演示中看到的
Nice little size with the events
精巧的小尺寸 有事件
and the timer ticking.
还有计时器
We only have like an hour and
我们离聚会开始
twenty minutes until bash, so
只有一小时二十分钟了
hang in there.
请大家再坚持一下
So I'm going to send this.
我现在要把这个发送出去
There we go.
发送
It's in a transcript live and
这是在一个实时文本
the timer's ticking.
计时器正在运行
So this was a quick demo to how
以上就是关于如何使用 Live Message Layout 的
to adopt Live Message Layout.
快速演示的内容
So let's talk more about some of
我们再来讲讲
the interactions in
viewControlLifecycle 里的
viewControlLifecycle.
交互情况
I would actually like to bring
我很愿意邀请 Stephen
Stephen back on stage to talk
回到台上来
more about it.
讲讲这一点
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
Thank you Jay.
谢谢 Jay
All right.
好的
So, now we've seen a little bit
现在我们已经
of an introduction of what it
简单地了解过
looks like to use the new API,
这个新 API 使用时的状况
to use Live Message Layouts in
以及在 iMessage 应用里使用
your iMessage app.
Live Message Layout 是什么情况
If you'll think back to the demo
如果你回想一下
I did at the beginning of the
我在会议开始时做的演示
session, we had some interactive
我们当时已经看到了一些
elements to our iMessage app
出现在 iMessage 应用气泡框里的
bubbles.
交互元素
And so I'd actually like to
所以我现在很想
return to Xcode now to do just
回到 Xcode 来说明
that.
这一点
So return to my device here.
回到我的设备上
We're going to go back to Xcode
我们要回到 Xcode 上
just where we left off.
回到我们之前离开的位置
And I'm going to get my device
我要让我的设备
ready for this demo.
进入演示准备状态
Excellent.
很好
Okay. So the first thing we want
好了 我们要做的第一件事就在这里
to do is here we have this
现在我们有了这个
EventCountdownTranscriptView and
EventCountdownTranscriptView
that's the view that gets
这个视图
imbedded in that app message in
嵌在这个应用信息的文本中
the transcript and so we want to
所以我们要
configure that with some inner
为这个视图配置一些
activity.
内部活动
So I'm going to go ahead and
我要直接开始
jump into that class and you'll
跳到这个分类
see that I have a number of
你会发现  我有很多
properties here that are
已配置的属性
configured, and here in
那么现在
setupSubviews I have a tap
在这个 setupSubview 里
adjuster recognizer that's set
我创建了一个 tapGestureRecognizer
up so that when the user taps my
所以当用户轻点我的视图时
view this method user to tap
userDidTap 方法
gets called.
就会被调用
If I jump to the implementation,
如果我直接跳至执行
of course the implementation
当然这个执行
right now is empty and it's
现在还是空白的
ready for us to add something.
正等着我们来添加内容
So the inner activity we'll want
我们首先要添加的
to add first is specifically
内部活动是
when the app message represents
在应用信息显示
an unaccepted invitation.
一项未接受邀请时开始
So if the event is not for me or
如果这个事件与我无关
if the app message is not for me
或应用信息不是给我的
and it's not been accepted then
而且未被接受
we want to have that interactive
然后我们想给它添加
element to it.
交互元素
So the first thing we'll do is
首先我们要做的就是
say if is not accepted and it's
如果没有被接受
not from me then we'll change
且不是给我的
our view flag to have is
我们就要把视图旗标改为
accepted equals true.
让 isAccepted 等于 True
And the other thing I want to do
我们要做的另一件事
is update the model that I have
是更新我现在的这个
here.
模型
Normally I would use correct MVC
通常我会使用正确的 MVC
and also update maybe my service
可能还会更新我的设备
to indicate that the event has
以表明该事件
been updated, but for the
已更新
purposes of this demo I'm just
但为了便于演示
going to mark this in the
我会在默认配置中直接对此
defaults.
进行标记
Great. So I've updated some
很好 我已经更新了某个状态
state now I need to update my
现在我需要更新我的视图状态
view state, so I'll just use a
我会在这里使用
quick animation block here to
一个快速的动画块
call into my updated view state
来调用已更新的视图状态
and then I'll trigger a layout
然后我将触发一个布局
pass.
传递
Now this updateViewState, it
现在再看这个 updateViewState
just looks at the different
它刚在我的视图上查看了
flags and properties on my view
不同的旗标和属性
and configures the view
并正确地配置这个
correctly.
视图
So wait for our demo device to
所以等我们的演示设备
come back up and I'll show you
恢复正常 我会向大家展示
what that looks like in
实际情况
practice.
是什么样的
Great. So here we have our
很好 现在我们
unaccepted invitation being
在演示中
shown in our demo and it's ready
展示了未接收的邀请
for us to test out that
我们已经准备好测试
interaction that we just added.
刚刚添加的交互
So if you see that when I tap
大家看 当我轻点这条信息时
that message that state gets
状态就得到了更新
updated and we see that live
我们可以看到实时的倒计时
countdown, and you can tell that
大家可以看到
I have very little time left so
我剩下时间已经很少了
I better keep going.
所以我最好抓紧
Now the one thing that we're
现在 我们在这里
missing here is that nice
遗漏了一样东西
infoButton on the top right that
就是右上角那个漂亮的 infoButton
really gave me that rich detail
这个按钮提供了大量
about the event that I don't
有关此事的详情
want to necessarily put here in
我不想也不需要把这些信息
my app message.
放在我的 App 信息里
So if I go back to the code here
如果我回到代码
you'll see that this infoButton
大家会看到这个 infoButton
is just waiting to be
正在等待
implemented.
执行
But before we do that, we need
但是在执行之前
to add the infoButton to the
我们要把这个 infoButton 添加到
view hierarchy.
视图层级里
So here in setupSubViews you can
在这个 setupSubViews 里你可以
see that I have this infoButton
看到我有这个 infoButton
that's already been configured,
它已经配置好了
including with that target
还包括了我正好需要
action I just need to add it as
添加为 subView 的
a sub view.
目标动作
I also want to add some
我还想添加一些约束
constraints like it's laid out
比如使该视图布局
properly.
合理化
And then we'll go and jump into
然后我们继续
the implementation for
跳至
infoButtonTapped and call into
infoButtonTapped 的执行并
our delegate.
调用我们的委托代理
Now the delegate of this view is
现在这个视图的委托代理
our app view controller, and the
是我们的应用视图控制器
app view controller is the
这个应用视图控制器
object that knows how to change
是一个知道如何改变
presentation styles, so I need
展示风格的对象
to call out to it.
所以我需要将其调出
You'll see that this method
你会看到  这个方法
hasn't been implemented yet in
尚未被执行
my delegate.
但在我的委托代理当中
So we're going to jump over to
所以我们要快速
that delegate really quick.
跳至这个委托代理
Here is a delegate protocol
这是一个委托协议声明
declaration where we see that
我们可以看到
method hasn't been defined.
这个方法尚未被定义
So go ahead and add it.
所以我们直接添加上去
And then we'll jump over to
然后我们跳转到
where this protocol is
这个协议执行的地方
implemented and add our new
把我们刚刚添加的
method that we just added.
新方法添加进去
Now all we need to do is request
现在我们所要做的就是
that new presentation style and
请求这个新的展示风格
that's it.
就是这样
When I do that, the app view
我这样做的时候
controller requests that new
应用视图控制器会请求
presentation style and Messages
这个新的展示风格
will instantiate the new view
Message 应用会在扩展展示中
controller in that expanded
把这个新的视图控制器
presentation.
充实进去
So this is the same thing that
这就是刚刚
was just implemented here in the
在代码中执行的同一种
code.
东西
We have the infoButton in the
我们在右上角有了这个 infoButton
top right, and when you tap it
当你轻点这个按钮时
we get that nice expanded
我们就可以得到漂亮的
presentation with the additional
扩展展示和其他额外的
content.
内容
So that's it.
就是这样
We have a completed demo that's
我们给大家提供了
showing you -- thank you.
一次完整的演示--谢谢
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
So with the completed demo you
通过这一次完整的演示
see that we can add completely
大家可以看到我们能够
custom layouts that really add
添加完整的自定义布局
some richness to that experience
这确实可以让我们对文本的体验
in the transcript, including
变得更加丰富
inner activity and live updating
包括它的内部活动和实时更新
content.
内容
So when we think about
当我们想与这些
interaction with these live
实时信息布局
message layouts, we really want
进行交互时
to keep it simple.
我们只希望保持一种简单
Stick to simple button taps and
继续使用简单的按钮触发和
tap gestures, and let me use the
轻点手势  并且让我使用
scroll views.
滚动视图
This app message is being
这个 App 信息将被
imbedded in a fairly complicated
嵌入一个相当精巧的用户界面
UI, the Messages transcript, and
即 Message 文本里
the user's used to interactions
用户将会习惯于
like vertically scrolling the
这些交互方式
transcript, horizontally
例如上下滚动文本
scrolling the transcript, and
左右滚动文本
other gestures that take place.
以及其他可用的手势
And so if you add too many
如果你在其中添加了过多
complicated things here it can
复杂的东西
be disorienting to the user.
就会让用户感觉很混乱
The other thing to remember is
另外 要记住的一件事是
that there's no keyboard input
这些应用信息视图
allowed for these app message
并不采用键盘输入方式
views, and so if you want
如果你想要
keyboard input you should
使用键盘输入
request an expanded presentation
就应该请求一个扩展展示风格
style where your app can use the
这样你的 App 就能够使用
keyboard.
键盘了
Now these views are really light
出于某种原因
weight for a reason.
这些实际上都是轻量级的视图
When you think about their
大家想一想它们的
lifecycle, they're only
生命周期
instantiated when the user comes
它们只有在用户进入对话
into the conversation to look at
并进行查看时  才会充实具体
it.
内容
As soon as the user leaves the
只要用户离开对话
conversation or leaves the app,
或离开这个 App
your iMessage app will be torn
你的 iMessage 应用就会
down.
解除使用
So it's not an appropriate place
所以这些视图里不适合
to put something like a 3D game
加入 3D 游戏引擎这样的
engine.
东西
If you do want to do that, you
如果你确实想这么做
should request that expanded
你应该请求
presentation style for the user
扩展展示风格
to take part in your extended
让用户参与你的
interaction.
扩展交互
Now I want to cover this again
现在我想再说一下这个问题
because I think this is
因为我觉得这
important.
很重要
When requesting the expanded
当你在请求
presentation style, your
扩展展示风格时
transcript app view controller
你的文本应用视图控制器
is not reconfigured with new
并没有被重新配置成
presentation style -- it's left
新的展示风格
in place in the transcript.
而只是留在了文本里
If no view controller exist in
如果没有视图控制器
the compact or expanded
是以简洁或扩展
presentation style, Messages
展示的风格存在
will instantiate a new object,
Message 会充实一个新的对象
configure it accordingly, and
并对它进行相应的配置
then add it and show it here.
然后在这里添加它  展示它
If one does exist then it will
如果这类风格的视图控制器确实已经存在
reconfigure it to the new
Message 会将其重新配置为
presentation style.
新的展示风格
And this is specifically if it
这是在某个简洁或
already has one that is compact
扩展风格的视图控制器确实存在时
or expanded.
一种特殊的对待方法
It will then change the selected
这样一来  这个视图控制器上的选中信息
message on that view controller
就会发生变化
and you will get the didn't
你可以把
select message callback on that
在这个视图控制器上
view controller.
调回未选中的信息调回
Now the transcript app view
现在这个文本应用视图控制器
controller that's left in place
按照原样留在原位
as is or the static selected
或是处于静态选中信息的状态
message because it always
因为它始终
represents that message in the
在显示这个文本中的
transcript.
信息
Now when we talk about lifecycle
下面我们稍微谈一谈
a little more of your iMessage
iMessage 应用的生命周期问题
app, in iOS 10 these methods on
在 iOS 10 里 这些
MSMessagesAppViewController
MSMessagesAppViewController 的方法
applied specifically to your
将专门应用于
extension lifecycle because
你的扩展生命周期
there was only one instance of
因为只有一个
the view controller created and
视图控制器的实例得以创建
it was closely coupled with the
它与你的 iMessage App 的
lifecycle of your iMessage app,
生命周期紧密结合
so you could rely on it for
所以你可以依靠它来
extension lifecycle
获得扩展生命周期的
notification.
通知
However, in iOS 11, we can
然而在 iOS 11 里
instantiate many instances of
我们可以为你的主要分类
your principle class.
充实众多例证
So these methods really pertain
这些方法确实和视图控制器的
more to the view controller
生命周期关联更大
lifecycle and you need to think
你需要从这个角度
of it from that perspective.
来进行思考
If you do need to pay attention
如果你需要关注
to extension lifecycle events of
自己的 iMessage 应用里的
your iMessage app, you should
扩展生命周期事件
observe the NS extension related
就应该遵循与 NSExtension 相关的
notifications.
通知
Now in a particular instance of
现在 在一个已经创建的
your transcript app view
文本应用视图控制器的
controller is created, the
特定实例中
lifecycle methods proceed like
生命周期方法就是这样
this.
展开的
First, we'll initialize the view
首先 我们把视图控制器进行初始化
controller and call viewDidLoad.
再调用 viewDidLoad
Then we'll call willBecomeActive
然后我们调用 willBecomeActive
and didBecomeActive with
和 didBecomeActive
conversation as part of the
并且把对话作为
Messages API contract.
Message API 合约的一部分
Then the view appearance methods
然后 当你的视图控制器
will be called as your view
被嵌入视图层级并加以显示时
controller is inserted into the
视图显示方法
view hierarchy for display.
随即会被调用
Lastly, contentSizeThatFits will
最后 contentSizeThatFits 将会
be called.
被调用
Now when willBecomeActive and
现在 当 willBecomeActive
didBecomeActive with
和 didBecomeActive
conversation are called, you
和对话一起被调用时
have all the information you
你将获得所需的全部信息
need to correctly configure your
从而可以通过查看
view controller by looking at
视图控制器中的展示风格
that presentation style and
和选定信息
selected message on the view
来正确地配置
controller.
你的视图控制器
Now when thinking about
现在我们想一想
contentSizeThatFits getting
contentSizeThatFits 是
called last, this is because it
最后被调用的  原因在于
may be called multiple times.
它可能会被多次调用
Think about the Messages
我们可以想一想  Message 应用程序
application on an iPad in split
在一台 iPad 上 以分割视图模式
view mode.
呈现出来的样子
As the user changes the size of
当用户更改
the Messages app, the metrics of
Message 应用的尺寸时
the Messages application, and
Message 应用的衡量标准会改变
therefore the transcript,
因此其文本也会随之
change.
改变
We'll then call into your
然后我们
contentSizeThatFits method with
以更新的尺寸或最大的尺寸
an updated size or maximum size,
来调用你的 contentSizeThatFits 方法
and you should update your app
你要相应地更新
size accordingly.
你的 App 尺寸
It can also be, of course,
它当然也可以随着
updated for dynamic text size
动态文本尺寸更改和
changes and locale changes.
区域更改而更新
The last thing I want to cover
最后我想说的问题是
is pending messages.
待发送信息
Now remember, your view
请记住
controller can be configured to
你的视图控制器可以获得配置
represent app messages in a
并将呈现以某种文本展示风格
transcript presentation style
而呈现的 App 信息
both for an unsent message and
既可以用于未发送信息
the message that has been sent
也可以用于已经在文本形式下
in the transcript.
发送的信息
Now most of the time you should
绝大多数时候
keep the same application view
你要让同一个应用视图
in both states because the user
同时保持这两种状态
is really previewing the content
因为用户确实会预览
that's going to be sent here.
将在这里发送的内容
But if you do need to
但如果你确实需要
differentiate between the two,
将两者区分开来
you can check the isPending flag
你可以查看 isPending 旗标
which is a new property on
这是 MSMessage 上的一个新属性
MSMessage that will let you know
它可以让你知道
the difference between these two
这两种状态之间的
states.
区别
So that's all we have for you
以上就是今天为大家介绍的
today to introduce Live Message
Live Message Layout 的
Layouts.
全部内容
Remember, this is interactive
记住 这是以文本呈现的
iMessage apps in the transcript,
各类交互性 iMessage 应用
which I think is incredibly cool
我觉得这样做简直酷得要命
and I can't wait to see what you
我很期待能看到大家对它
build with it.
进行创建开发
We're using the same MSMessage
我们使用的是同样的
app view controller sub class,
MSMessage 应用视图控制器子类
and the new layout, the
以及新的布局
MSMessagesLiveLayout with a new
即拥有新展示风格的
presentation style for you to
MSMessagesLiveLayout
use as a tool to build these
你可以以此作为工具
rich new experiences.
开发这些丰富的新体验
I'm really looking forward to
我真的非常期待看到
what you build with this and I
大家利用它来进行开发的成果
think you're going to come up
我认为你们会
with things that we haven't even
遇到我们尚未
thought of yet.
想明白的东西
And with that, I'd like to bring
为此 我想请
up Eugene to introduce some best
Eugene 来介绍一些
practices when using the
使用 Message 框架时的
Messages framework.
最佳操作
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; All right.
&gt;&gt; 好的
Thank you, Stephen.
谢谢 Stephen
Live Message Layouts, super
Live Message Layout
exciting.
超级激动人心
So we want to wrap up our talk
在今天讲座的最后
today with just a couple best
我们要分享几个
practices tips and tricks for
iMessage 应用的
your iMessage apps just to give
最佳操作技巧
your apps that little extra
从而给大家的应用增加一点
shine and polish that we think
额外的闪光点
will make them look really
我们认为这会让应用真正变得
great.
很棒
So, we have a couple of tips for
所以 我们今天为大家
you guys today.
准备了几个小技巧
Let's get into it.
我们现在就开始吧
So the first thing we'd like to
首先我想讲讲
talk about is the iMessage app
iMessage 应用的
area insets.
区域嵌入
So this is the area at the
看这个区域  它位于
bottom of the screen underneath
屏幕底部
the app strip as well as at the
在应用条的下方
bottom of the screen in expanded
同时也位于扩展模式下的
mode.
屏幕底部
So similar to like navigation
它跟同导航控制器很相似
controllers, Messages UI can
Message UI 可以
include the area displayed by
包含你的应用所展示的区域
your application so you can have
所以你可以
that nice blurred effect when
在滚动视图时
scrolling scroll views.
获得漂亮的模糊效果
So to determine your app area
要想确定你的应用区域嵌入
insets, you can look at the
你可以查看
UIViewController top and bottom
UIViewController 顶部及底部的
layout guides, or new in iOS 11
布局指南 或在 iOS 11 的新功能中
check out UIViewsafeAreaInsets.
查看 UIViewsafeAreaInsets
These will define all the areas
这些东西将会界定你的
of your application's view that
在 Message UI 里所有未被遮蔽的
are un occluded by Messages UI.
应用视图区域
Of course, you can always use
当然 你也可以一直
Autolayout to add constraints to
使用 Autolayout 来添加对
the UIViewController's top and
UIViewController 的顶部或
bottom layout guides.
底部布局指南的约束
So for applications linked on
对于连接到 iOS 10 的应用
iOS 10, we will continue to use
我们将继续使用
old legacy insets.
旧版的嵌入
But a great way to keep up with
但有一个很好的办法可以
the change in UI Messages and
跟进 UI Messages 的改变
have your application adapt
并让你的应用进行合理调整
appropriately is to properly
那就是适当地
adopt either the
采用
UIViewsafeAreaInsets or
UIViewsafeAreaInsets 或
UIViewController top and bottom
UIViewController 顶部和底部的
layout guides.
布局指南
Next up we have message summary
下面我们介绍一下信息摘要
text.
文本
So iOS 10 introduced MSMessage
iOS 10 推出了 MSMessage
and a property on it called
以及它名为 summaryText
summaryText.
的属性
In iOS 10, summaryText was used
在 iOS 10 里  summaryText 被用于
for Messages with an MS Session
附有 MS Session 的信息
attached to it, so kind of
这是一种
session based messaging and we'd
基于会话的信息传递
insert a very small succinct
我们将插入一个简明扼要的摘要
summary inline the transcript of
来内联这个信息的
that message.
文本
In iOS 11, we are expanding the
在 iOS 11 中 我们
use of the summaryText property
将 summaryText 属性的使用
to all MSMessages sent.
扩展到了所有已发送的 MSMessages
So where do you see the
那么你可以在哪里
summaryText?
看到 summaryText 呢
MSMessage summaryText will now
MSMessage summaryText 现在将
be used in the conversation list
用于对话列表预览
preview as well as places like
以及通知中心等领域
notification center so you can
这样你就可以
give context to your
把语境提供给
application's message
你应用程序的
notifications.
信息通知
So this is a really great way
所以这是一个很好的方式
for users at a quick glance to
用户可以快速浏览
see the content that you send in
你在应用信息中
your app message.
发送的内容
So iOS 11 summaryText and every
以上就是 iOS 11 中的 summaryText
single one here, MSMessages.
和每一个单项内容  MSMessages
Next up we have stickers.
接下来介绍的是贴纸
So the introduction of sticker
自从 iOS 10 引入贴纸包后
packs in iOS 10 we're seeing
我们见证了
tons of them released.
无数贴纸的发布
I absolutely love them, download
我特别喜欢贴纸
new ones every week.
每周都会下载一批新的
Keep up the awesome work on the
密切关注那些超赞的
sticker packs.
贴纸包作品
We love it.
我们喜爱它
We do want to give a couple tips
我们想分享几条技巧
about making your sticker packs
让大家的贴纸包
faster and send quicker.
使用起来更快速 发送更便捷
Overall, sticker pack
总的来说
performance is a function of
贴纸包的运行是
your sticker's file size.
关于贴纸文件大小的函数
This function of the sticker's
这个函数
file size is a function of your
是关于你的贴纸
sticker's pixel size as well as
像素大小以及帧率的
its frame rate.
函数
A really great resource for you
有一个非常好的资源
to look at is the Messages Human
可以用来参考
Interface Guidelines which is
它就是 Messages Human Interface Guidelines
available in the developer
这个可以在开发者门户网站获取
portal which will tell you the
这个指南将会告诉你
target sticker sizes for either
我们所支持的
the small, medium or large
目标贴纸的尺寸
stickers that we support.
包括大中小尺寸的贴纸
In addition, consider the frame
另外 还有贴纸的
rate of your sticker.
帧率也要考虑到
Stickers with higher frame rates
具有较高帧率
or longer loop times have a
或循环时间较长的贴纸
higher memory overhead and will
会产生较大的内存开销
negatively impact the
对贴纸应用的运行也会
performance of your sticker
产生负面影响
application as well as
并对发送时间
So for quick fast sending
因此 为了快速发送贴纸
stickers and quick launching
快速启动贴纸应用
sticker apps, make sure your
请确保你的
stickers are sized correctly and
贴纸尺寸正确
either use short loops or lower
并使用短时间的循环  或是较低的
frame rates.
帧率
So looking forward to seeing all
我非常期待见到
the new sticker packs you guys
大家在 iOS 11 中设计的
make in iOS 11 as well.
新贴纸包
And last up on our list is
我们最后要讲的是
MFMessageComposeViewController.
MFMessageComposeViewController
MSMessageComposeViewController
MFMessageComposeViewController 是
is the Messages share sheet that
Message 的 Share Sheet
can be invoked from your parent
从你的父级应用程序里
application.
即可调用
So in iOS 10 we introduced a new
在 iOS 10 中 我们在 Share Sheet
property on the share sheet
添加了新属性
called Message, which
它名为 Message
predictably takes an MSMessage
可以预先应用 MSMessage
instance.
实例
So if you already have an
如果你已经有
iMessage app, your parent
一个 iMessage 应用
companion app can actually send
你的父级伴随 App 其实可以
the same application balloons
发送同样的应用汽球框
either a template layout or a
或者是一个模板布局
live Layout that you can send in
或者是 liveLayout 你都可以
the Messages app itself.
在 Message 应用里发送
So you get a very nice
这样你就会得到非常不错
consistent sharing experience
而且连贯一致的分享体验
between your parent application
在你的父级应用
and your iMessage app.
和 iMessage 应用之间进行分享
App balloons that are received,
接收到的 App 汽球框
can either then be opened within
要么能够在
your iMessage app or can bounce
你的 iMessage 应用里打开
the user out to their parent
要么能够通过 open URL 命令
application via the open URL
将用户弹至其父级应用
command.
程序
So definitely take a look at
所以一定要关注
Message property on
MFMessageComposeViewController 中的
MFMessageComposeViewController.
Message 属性
And with that we've wrapped up
以上就是我们总结的
our tips!
一些小技巧
Just a couple things for
有几件事
everyone to keep in mind.
需要大家牢记在心
Look at your layout margins.
注意查看布局边距
Set summaryText on all
在 iOS 11 的所有 MSMessage 上
MSMessages in iOS 11.
设置 summaryText
Consider sticker sizes and frame
注意贴纸的尺寸和帧率
rate for faster sticker packs.
以便让贴纸包更快速
And also keep on making awesome
同时也要继续设计
stickers.
那些超赞的贴纸噢
And finally, you can now send
最后 大家现在可以从
app balloons from
MFMessageComposeViewController
MFMessageComposeViewController.
发送 App 汽球框了
So certainly check that out for
一定要试试这个
consistent user experience.
从而感受到连贯一致的用户体验
So what did we learn today?
我们今天都了解到哪些事情了呢
We went over a couple new things
我们了解到
with MSMessages app UI.
MSMessages App UI 的一些新特性
We saw the direct send API for
我们了解到 Direct Send API
an awesome new setting
可以在你的 iMessage 应用里
experience in your iMessage
进行超赞的全新设置
apps.
Stephen 和 Jay 带着大家
Live Message Layouts.
了解到了 Live Message Layout
I cannot wait to see what all of
我极其期待看到
you build with that.
大家的相关开发成果
And finally, a couple best
最后是几条
practices tips and tricks.
最佳操作技巧
If you'd like more information
如果大家想了解更多信息
check out our session webpage
可以访问我们会议的网页
right here.
就是这个网址
In addition, we also have a
除此之外  我们还有
couple related sessions
几场相关会议
happening tomorrow.
将在明天进行
We have, at 10:00 a.m. in this
上午 10:00 的一场 就在这个会议厅
hall, Introducing Business Chat,
主题是“介绍 Business Chat”
which I know all of you are
我觉得大家
probably really excited to hear
可能都对它极度地
about.
感兴趣
In addition, we are very lucky
另外 在今年的会议中
this year to have one of our
我们非常荣幸地请来了
Messages HI designers who will
我们 Message 应用的 HI 设计者
be doing a design short tomorrow
明天上午 11:00 在行政宴会厅
at 11:00 a.m. in the Executive
他将简短地演示一下
Ballroom.
设计过程
Thank you for being here tonight
谢谢大家的参与
and enjoy the bash!
祝大家聚会愉快
Thank you!
谢谢